TINSAYE ALAKO ABIYO

:+251991221912

M:tinsingjobs2k@gmail.com

♥: Gerji, Addis Ababa

Python Developer

Date of Birth: 02/08/1998

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single

Nationality: Ethiopia

I am an experienced Python developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Django stack and Machine learning stack. I am

skilled in python and j related frameworks like Django, Tensorflow and Keras. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering from Mekelle University. I am very passionate and hardworking, with a penchant for meeting deadlines and solving problems. I believe in frequent communication with clients and stakeholders.

Work Experience

January 2021 -January 2023

Backend Developer

Serdo Software Plc

Developing and maintaining the database that stores the company's product inventory, customer data, and order information

Developing and maintaining the web services that allow users to browse the company's products, add items to their cart, and checkout

Developing and maintaining the payment processing system that allows users to pay for their purchases

Developing and maintaining the security systems that protect the company's data from unauthorized acces

January 2019 – February 2023

Full Stack Developer

Arbamich University

Arbaminch,

SNNPR

Developed and maintained front-end components and features for university's alumni association.

Collaborate with back-end developers and designers to ensure seamless integration of front-end and back-end systems.

Create responsive and accessible web designs that work well on a variety of devices and browsers.

Optimize web designs for performance and ensure they load quickly and run smoothly. Test and debug web applications to ensure they are bug-free and performant.

Continuously research and learn new front-end technologies and techniques.

February 2020 - Full Stack Developer

May 2022

January 2018 - July 2020

Ashewa.com

Design and develop the front-end of a web application, including the user interface and user experience.

 Develop the back-end of a web application, including the underlying code, databases, and web services.

Work with designers and other stakeholders to ensure that the application meets the needs of the user.

- Test and debug the application to ensure that it is working properly.
- Deploy the application to a production environment.
 Maintain and update the application as needed.

Django Developer

Guzogo

Designing and developing the back-end of a web application, including the underlying code, databases, and web services.

Working with designers and other stakeholders to ensure that the application meets the needs of the user.

- Testing and debugging the application to ensure that it is working properly.
 Deploying the application to a production environment.
- Maintaining and updating the application as needed.
- Design and develop the front-end of a web application, including the user interface and user experience.

Develop the back-end of a web application, including the underlying code, databases, and web services.

 Work with designers and other stakeholders to ensure that the application meets the needs of the user.

Test and debug the application to ensure that it is working properly.

- Deploy the application to a production environment.
- · Maintain and update the application as needed.

Education

January 2018 -January 2023

Software Engineering - Mekelle University

January 2022 -August 2023

Bachelor Of Engineering

Web And Mobile Development - Arba Minch University Bachelor Of Engineering

Mekelle, Tigray.

Arba Minch, SNNPR.

Skills

React Native Nextjs 13 Typescript Nodejs Nestjs React Javascript Django Stack **Express** Software Parrot Ubunto Σ Hobbies Window Gym Bro Learning New Technologies And Framework Peer To Peer Chat With Work Mates

Referees

Ato Amanuel Minas

Unit Manager (Ashewa Technologies) +251912444473

Ato Dagmawi Geberemariam
Project Manager (Ashewa Technologies)
+251965200926